Encounters are mysterious! But cases are even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والقضايا تلفّها طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today is the lemon pie conclusion!
!اليوم ختام فطيرة الليمون
Fragrant memories and tender first love!
!ذكريات فوّاحة وحب أوّل رقيق
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
We were invited to the birthday party of Uchida Asami,
،تمّت دعوتنا لحفلة عيد ميلاد أوتشيدا أسامي
rumored to have been Shinichi's first love.
التي يُشاع أنّها الحُب الأوّل لشينتشي
She fell asleep, so the rest of us went to the Karaoke Room in town.
غطّت في النوم، فتركناها وتوجّهنا لغرفة الكاراوكي في المدينة
That's when one of her friends noticed the lodge was on fire!
!لاحظ أحد رفاقها آنذاك نشوب حريق في النزل
Uchida Asami was asleep in the lodge!
!كانت أوتشيدا أسامي نائمةً في النزل
Luckily, Ran broke down the door and managed to save her!
لحسن الحظّ، حطّمت ران الباب وتمكّنت من إنقاذها
"The Memories of First Love Case (Part 2)."
قضيّة ذكريات الحُب الأوّل (الجزء الثاني)
Eh?! She said that in her sleep?!
!ماذا؟ قالت أسامي سينباي ذلك في نومها؟
Not so loud! You'll wake her up!
!صوتك مرتفع! ستوقظينها
As I was saying, she was sleep-mumbling when they brought her here.
كما قلت، كانت تتمتم في نومها عندما نقلوها إلى هنا
"I'm sorry! I'm sorry, Kudo-kun! I'm so sorry!"
"!آسفة! آسفة يا كودو-كن! أنا آسفة"
But why would she say that?
لكن لمَ قد تقول ذلك؟
How should I know? That's just what I heard.
لا أدري! ذلك ما سمعتُه فحسب
Anyways, are you thirsty?
بأيّ حال، أتشعرين بعطش؟
I can get you something from the vending machine downstairs!
يمكنني أن أشتري لك شيئاً من آلة البيع في الأسفل
I'll come with you, then.
سأرافقك إذاً
Say, is Conan-kun all right?
بالمناسبة، هل كونان-كن بخير؟
Yeah! He's perfectly okay! Not a scratch on him!
!أجل، إنّه بخير تماماً! مُتعافٍ
I bet he's with your dad, loitering around the scene of the fire.
لا بدّ أنّه مع أبيك يتجوّلان في مسرح الحريق
Was it really an accident? Did they just forget to put out the candles?
أكان حادثاً حقّاً؟ أنسوا إطفاء الشموع فقط؟
If so, then why was she asleep on the sofa when we left
في تلك الحالة، لمَ كانت أسامي-سان التي نامت على الأريكة
but on the floor during the fire?
مستلقيةً على الأرض بين النيران؟
And this room...
...وهذه الغرفة
Something seems off about the furniture before and after the fire!
بدا الأثاث مختلفاً بشكل ما من قبل الحريق عن بعده
Almost as if someone moved it!
!كما لو أنّ أحداً حرّكه
Could it be?! Did someone come back here to set the fire?!
أيمكن أنّ أحداً رجع هنا لإضرام النار؟
If so, then Morimoto-san would be most suspicious, as he had the key!
في تلك الحالة، سيكون موريموتو-سان الأكثر شبهة بما أنّه كان يملك المفتاح
No, wait!
...كلا، انتظر
Anyone could've easily entered via a window unlocked in advance!
كان بإمكان أيّ أحد الدخول بسهولة عبر نافذة مفتوحة القفل سلفاً
Think! Think!
!فكّر! فكّر
According to the witnesses, the fire started around 2:50.
وفقاً لشهود عيان، بدأ الحريق عند قرابة الثانية وخمسين دقيقة
We were all in the karaoke booth at 3:00.
كنّا جميعاً في حجرة الكاراوكي عند الثالثة
By car, it'd take five minutes to get here. Running, it'd take fifteen.
ستستغرق 5 دقائق للوصول إلى هناك بالسيّارة من هنا، و15 دقيقة ركضاً
No one was gone for thirty minutes,
،لم يغب أحد لثلاثين دقيقة
so only Noguchi-san could've gone there, set the fire, and returned,
فكان نوغوتشي-سان هو الوحيد القادر على الذهاب هناك وإضرام النار والعودة
since he had the car key...
بما أنّ مفتاح السيّارة معه
The car was parked in front of the karaoke place,
،كانت السيّارة مركونةً أمام محلّ الكاراوكي
and everyone left thirty minutes before to use the station bathrooms
وغادر الجميع قبل 30 دقيقة لاستعمال دورة مياه المحطّة
and buy cigarettes and such from the convenience store next door.
وشراء أغراض من متجر التموينات بالجوار
So someone would've noticed if the car was missing.
فكان ليلاحظ أحد اختفاء السيّارة
If not the car... Chika-san's motorcycle?!
إذا لم تكن بالسيّارة، فربما درّاجة تشيكا-سان الناريّة؟
No, it was parked in front of the lodge when we rushed here.
كلا، كانت مركونةً أمام النزل عندما وصلنا هنا
It's impossible!
!مستحيل
None of the people in the karaoke booth could've done it!
لم يستطع أحد المتواجدين في حجرة !الكاراوكي آنذاك ارتكاب الجريمة
It'd be a different story if there was a timer device of some sort,
سيكون الموضوع مختلفاً لو كان هنا ،جهاز توقيت ما
but if there had been one, the firemen would've found it long ago.
لكن كان ليجده رجال الإطفاء لو كان ذلك صحيحاً
Which leaves what the old guy said... It was Asami-san who...
...مما يترك ما قاله العمّ فقط... كانت أسامي-سان بنفسها من
Hold it, little boy!
انتبه يا فتى
You know you shouldn't be in here.
لا يجدر بك الدخول هنا
I'm sorry!
آسف
Oh, yeah. I hear today's the birthday of that girl who was asleep.
بالمناسبة، سمعت أنّ اليوم كان عيد ميلاد الفتاة التي كانت نائمة هنا
The presents and the cake all burned up, but this survived the fire!
احترقت الهدايا والكعكة، لكن نجت هذه
Here you are!
هاك
It's a birthday message for her, right?
إنّها رسالة عيد ميلاد لها، صحيح؟
Go give it to her at the hospital.
أعطها إيّاها في المشفى
Huh? They don't fit!
!ماذا؟ لا تتوافق
Wait a minute! Come to think of it...
...انتظر، بالنظر مُجدداً
Come to think of it, that person did say something strange then!
بالنظر مُجدداً، قال ذاك الشخص شيئاً غريباً وقتها
Sheesh! Of course there was a fire!
!يا إلهي، لا عجب أنّ حريقاً قد نشب
The cake with the lit candles was sitting on a chair!
!كانت الكعكة بالشموع المشتعلة فوق كرسيّ
Say, Mister. Was the cake really on a chair?
أخبرني يا عمّ، أكانت الكعكة على كرسيّ حقّاً؟
Yeah. The chair was burnt up, and the cake turned to goop.
أجل، كان الكرسيّ محترقاً، والكعكة مفتّتة
Where was this chair?
أين كان ذاك الكرسيّ؟
It's right over there.
هناك
In front of that small, charred cabinet in the corner.
أمام الخزانة الصغيرة المحترقة في الزاوية
But doesn't it seem strange to you, Ran?
لكن ألا يبدو ذلك غريباً يا ران؟
What do you mean?
ماذا؟
I heard she was in the tennis club until her 2nd year of middle school.
سمعت أنّ أسامي-سان كانت في نادي كرة المضرب حتّى سنتها الثانية في المتوسّطة
And she was the national champion that year!
!وكانت البطلة الوطنيّة ذاك العام
Wow, that's amazing.
لا بدّ أنّها كانت مذهلة
Huh? But wasn't she the soccer club manager in her 3rd year?
ماذا؟ لكن ألم تكن مديرة نادي كرة القدم في سنتها الثالثة؟
Yeah! Apparently she completely changed after that summer break!
أجل! وقد تغيّرت تماماً بعد !العطلة الصيفية وفقما يبدو
I wonder why...
لمَ يا ترى؟
She probably wanted to focus on her studying.
لعلّها أرادت التركيز على الدراسة لا أكثر
But that'd be even weirder.
لكن سيكون ذلك أكثر غرابة
How come?
لمَ؟
The 2nd semester of the 3rd year is when people quit their clubs!
لأنّ الطلّاب يتركون أنديتهم في الفصل !الثاني من سنتهم الثالثة عادةً
That is strange, now that you mention it.
بذكركِ لذلك، الأمر غريب فعلاً
I bet she switched 'cause there were no hot guys in the tennis club.
لعلّها بدّلت لأنّه لم يكن هناك شبّان وسيمين في نادي كرة المضرب
Yeah, right. She isn't you.
لا يُعقل، فهي ليست أنت
Say what?
ما قصدك؟
Well, anyways, she must've had her reasons.
أيّاً يكن، لا بدّ أنّها كانت تملك دوافعها الخاصّة
It's probably none of our business to pry.
من الأفضل ألّا نتطفّل كثيراً
But I wanna know!
!لكنّي أريد أن أعرف
Not so loud! You'll wake her up!
!صوتك مرتفع! ستوقظينها
Huh?
ماذا؟
What? What is it?
ماذا هناك؟ ما الأمر؟
S-Senpai?
سـ-سينباي؟
Eh? Customers who came in at around 3:00?
ماذا؟ الزبائن الذين أتوا هنا عند الثالثة؟
Yeah! Do you remember who came?
أجل، أتذكر من أتاك؟
Let me think. Just some youngsters doing karaoke next door, I guess.
حسناً، كانوا شبّاناً يغنّون الكاراوكي في المحلّ المجاور وفقما أظنّ
They bought cigarettes, tomato juice, and other stuff.
اشتروا سجائراً وعصير طماطم وأشياء كهذه
What were they like?!
كيف كانوا؟
A brown-haired guy with glasses, a girl in a black dress,
،شاب بنيّ الشعر بنظّارات، وفتاة في فستان أسود
and a guy with a buzz-cut.
وشاب بقصّة شعر رياضيّة قصيرة
Sawai-san, Hayasaka-san, and Noguchi-san!
!إنّهم ساواي-سان وهاياساكا-سان ونوغوتشي-سان
Yeesh! That buzz-cut guy puked in front of the store!
!يا إلهي، تقيّأ صاحب قصّة الشعر الرياضيّة أمام المتجر
Cleaning it up was such a pain!
!كان التنظيف متعباً
Say, Mister. Could you tell me if...
...أخبرني يا عمّ، أيمكن أنّ
Sonoko! Any luck?!
سونوكو، أوجدتِها؟
No, she wasn't in the bathroom. How about you, Ran?
.كلا، لم تكن في دورة المياه ماذا عنك؟
No luck here, either.
لم أجدها هنا أيضاً
Where could Asami-senpai have gone?
أين ذهبت أسامي سينباي يا ترى؟
Just contact your dad for now! I'll go get a nurse!
بأيّ حال، أنتِ اتّصلي بأبيك وأنا سأذهب لجلب ممرضة
Right! Got it!
حسناً، فهمت
Yeah, that's right, little boy! How did you know that?
!أجل، كما قلت يا صبيّ كيف عرفت ذلك؟
Just as I thought.
كما ظننت
I told him he had it backwards, but he didn't listen.
أخبرتُه أنّها مقلوبة، لكنّه لم يستمع ليّ
It had sticky stuff on it, too. What a ridiculous customer.
،وكانت عليها أشياء دبقة أيضاً كان زبوناً عابثاً بحقّ
No question about it! That person set the fire!
!لا شكّ في الأمر، من أضرم الحريق كان ذاك الشخص
And if my theory is right, the evidence is still in their possession!
!وإن أصاب استنتاجي، فلا يزال الدليل معه
What?! Asami-san disappeared?!
!ماذا؟ اختفت أسامي-سان؟
Are you serious, Ran?!
أحقّاً هذا يا ران؟
Yeah! She was in bed just a minute ago!
أجل، كانت نائمةً على السرير قبل قليل
She must've left while we were getting something to drink!
لا بدّ أنّها غادرت بينما !ذهبنا لجلب شراب
What do we do, Dad?!
ماذا نفعل يا أبي؟
Just look around outside the hospital! She might still be nearby!
!ابحثوا بجوار المشفى بأيّ حال !قد لا تزال بالقرب
Okay.
حسناً
Where could Asami have gone?!
أين ذهبت أسامي؟
She may be planning to commit suicide.
لعلّها تنوي الانتحار
Suicide?!
!الانتحار؟
Yes. If it really was Asami-san who set the fire.
أجل، إن كانت أسامي-سان هي ...من أضرم هذا الحريق حقّاً
Or so one might think.
أو ما قد يخاله البعض
M-Mori-san?
موري-سان؟
But the truth is different.
لكنّ الحقيقة ليست كذلك
Asami-san was not the perpetrator but the victim!
!لم تكن أسامي-سان المجرمة، بل الضحيّة
Victim?!
الضحيّة؟
Yes. Asami-san was nearly burned to death.
كادت أسامي-سان تحترق موتاً
By one of you here!
!من فِعل أحدكم هنا
Y-You can't be serious!
!لا-لا يُعقل ذلك
But the fire started when we were in the karaoke booth!
فقد بدأ الحريق عندما كنّا في حجرة الكاراوكي، أليس كذلك؟
It'd take fifteen minutes to run from there to here.
ستحتاج 15 دقيقة للذهاب إلى هناك من هنا ركضاً
Or only five minutes by car or motorcycle.
وقرابة 5 دقائق بالسيّارة أو الدرّاجة النارية
The car didn't seem to have been used,
لكن لم يبد أنّ أحداً حرّك السيّارة
and the motorcycle was parked by this lodge.
وكانت الدرّاجة مركونةً أمام النزل
None of us could have come here to set the fire then.
يستحيل أن أحدنا استطاع القدوم هنا لإضرام الحريق
but the firefighters would've found it.
لكن كان رجال الإطفاء ليعثروا عليه
A timer device...
...جهاز توقيت
What if it was something not out of the ordinary?
ماذا لو كان شيئاً مألوفاً؟
that belonged there
ماذا لو كان شيئاً من الطبيعيّ تواجده هنا
and could be controlled from a remote location?
ويمكن التحكّم به عن بعد؟
Yes. The perpetrator set the fire from kilometers away!
أجل، أضرم الفاعل الحريق !من على بعد عدّة كيلومترات
By using a certain thing at a certain location near the karaoke place!
عبر استعمال شيء معيّن في مكان !مجاور لمحلّ الكاراوكي
Little boy! Everything's ready here!
!يا فتى! أنهينا التجهيزات
Okay! We'll be right there!
!حـ-حسناً! سنأتي الآن
Hey. What's ready?
أيّ تجهيزات؟
This man asked me to have the firefighters set up the same trick
طلب العمّ منّي أن أجعل رجال الإطفاء يعدّون حيلةً ما
that the bad guy used!
!مشابهة للتي استعملها الفاعل
What's so funny?
ما المضحك؟
It's just such a surprisingly simple trick!
!إنّها حيلة بسيطة لحدّ الدهشة
I bet it'll make you laugh, too!
لا بدّ أنّكم ستضحكون أيضاً
Oh, I see. It's set up like the living room before the fire.
فهمت، إنّها كغرفة المعيشة قبل الحريق
It even has a fax machine.
توجد آلة فاكس حتّى
So it does.
بالفعل
But how will this help?
لكن كيف سيفيد هذا؟
Pardon me!
اعذروني
Cake?
كعكة؟
That's right.
صحيح
I asked Conan to buy some just now.
طلبتُ من كونان شراء واحدة
If we place it on the chair in front of the fax machine, everything's set.
وإذا وضعناها على الكرسيّ أمام آلة الفاكس، ستكتمل التحضيرات
Now we just wait until it starts a fire.
ما بقي الآن هو أن ننتظر نشوب الحريق عند حلول الوقت
Uhh, Mori-san?
المعذرة، موري-سان؟
You're not suggesting we wait until a candle falls to the floor?
لا يمكن أنّك تطلب منّا انتظار سقوط الشمعة على الأرض صدفةً، صحيح؟
Besides, if that was what happened,
،كما حتّى لو حصل ذلك
that'd make it an accident caused by carelessness.
فسيكون مجرّد حادث من الإهمال
I would hardly call--
...لا يمكن اعتباره حيلة
A-A phone call?
ا-اتّصال؟
No, it's a fax!
!لا، إنّه فاكس
H-Hey!
...لـ-لحظة
You don't mean...
...أيمكن
That fax was sent by the convenience store owner at my request.
الفاكس الذي وصل الآن قد أرسله مالك متجر التموينات بطلبي
Just as the perpetrator sent one.
كما أرسله الفاعل قبله
You can't be serious...
...لا يُعقل
That's too simple!
...هذه حيلة بسيطة للغاية... لا يمكن أنّها
That was the perpetrator's intent.
كان ذلك هدف الفاعل
The more complicated the trick, the more likely evidence will be left.
كلّما تعقّدت الحيلة، ارتفع احتمال بقاء دليل في مسرح الجريمة
So the idea was to simplify the trick,
،لذا كانت الفكرة هي تبسيط الحيلة
leave as little out of the ordinary as possible,
والتأكّد من عدم بقاء أيّ آثار غير طبيعيّة
and make it look like an accidental fire.
فتبدو حريقاً غير مفتعل
Isn't that right?
ألستُ محقّاً؟
You went to the convenience store to buy cigarettes at that time...
يا من ذهب لمتجر التموينات بجوار ...محلّ الكاراوكي لشراء السجائر آنذاك
...Sawai Manabu-san!
ساواي مانابو-سان؟
Y-You did it, Sawai-kun?!
أ-أنت يا ساواي-كن؟
It's not true, right, President?!
لـ-ليس صحيحاً، أليس كذلك يا رئيس؟
B-But he leapt into the flames to rescue Asami!
!لـ-لكنّه اندفع داخل الحريق لإنقاذ أسامي
Would he really rescue someone he was trying to kill?!
أكان سيفعل ذلك لو كان ينوي قتلها حقّاً؟
Plus, he was the first to notice the fire!
!كما أنّه كان أوّل من لاحظ الحريق
What if he hadn't intended to kill her?
ماذا لو لم يكن ينوي قتلها؟
What if this fire was set so he could rescue Asami-san?
ماذا لو أضرم هذا الحريق بهدف إنقاذ أسامي-سان منذ البداية؟
Sawai-san most likely did the following...
...قام ساواي-سان بالتالي غالباً
He dropped sedatives into her drink to make her sleep,
...وضع حبوب منوّمة في شرابها، وجعلها تنام
set up the trick just now while everyone was getting ready to leave,
وجهّز الحيلة الآنفة الذكر بينما كان الجميع يتجهّزون للذهاب لمحلّ الكاراوكي
and then left the lodge.
ثمّ غادر النزل
To keep Asami-san from burning to death, he placed her on the floor,
وضع أسامي-سان على الأرض بعيداً عن أيّ قطع أثاث
far away from any furniture.
كي يحميها من الاحتراق حتى الموت
Then, just as he planned, while everyone was busy doing karaoke,
،ثمّ ووفق خطّته، بينما كان الجميع يلهون بالكاراوكي
he sent a fax to the lodge and started the fire.
أرسل فاكساً للنزل وأضرم الحريق
The store owner saw him sending the fax just before the fire started.
ودليلاً على ذلك، فقد رآه مالك متجر التموينات يرسل الفاكس قبل بدء الحريق
The burned remnants of that fax were also found.
وتمّ العثور على بقايا الفاكس المحترقة الذي أرسله أيضاً
Burned remnants?
بقايا محترقة؟
These! A firefighter gave them to me earlier!
!هذه! أعطاني إيّاها رجل إطفاء قبل قليل
See? The shapes don't fit, so there must've been two pages.
،انظروا، الشكل لا ينطبق فلا بدّ أنّها كانت صفحتين
Only one page was sent before the fire, so it seemed strange.
،أُرسلت صفحة واحد فحسب قبل الحريق فبدا ذلك غريباً
Right, Mister?
أليس كذلك يا عمّ؟
H-Hold on, now! Yes, I did send a fax at the convenience store.
ا-انتظر قليلاً! صحيحٌ أنّي استعملت آلة فاكس في متجر التموينات
But it was a fax I sent to a friend!
!لكنّي قد أرسلت الرسالة لأحد أصدقائي
He asked me to come up with a good title for his novel!
فقد طلب منّي التفكير بعنوان مناسب لروايته
Oh? A friend, huh?
حقّاً؟ صديق؟
Then how do you explain the transmit slip?
كيف تفسّر إيصال الإرسال إذاً؟
You gave the transmit slip to the store owner after you sent it, right?
أعطيت إيصال الإرسال لمالك المتجر بعدما استعملت آلة الفاكس، أليس كذلك؟
The date, time, phone number, and your fingerprints are on it.
عليه التاريخ والوقت ورقم الهاتف المُرسل إليه، كما بصماتك حتّى
Oh, that's strange. I'm sure I sent it to him.
ماذا؟ هذا غريب... أنا متأكّد أنّي أرسلته له
Just a minute.
انتظر قليلاً
Yes! I must've dialed the wrong number!
!فهمت، لا بدّ أنّي طلبت الرقم الخطأ
See? My friend's number and this lodge's number are next to each other.
انظر، رقم هاتف صديقي ورقم هاتف هذا النزل بجوار بعضهما
Besides, I'm president of Toto University's mystery study club!
كما أنّي رئيس نادي دراسة تحرّي جامعة توتو
I'd never use such an unreliable trick as that!
لن أستعمل حيلةً لا تستطيع التيقّن منها كهذه أبداً
That's why you tested it with a copy.
لذا اختبرتها بنسخة
When you set up the living room trick,
،عندما جهّزت هذه الحيلة في غرفة المعيشة
you used the fax machine's copy feature
استعملت خاصيّة النسخ لآلة الفاكس
to determine where it would catch fire.
لرؤية ما إن كانت ستسبّب الحريق حقّاً
As you know, to use the copy feature, you need to use an original.
كما تعون، تحتاج للورقة الأصليّة لطباعة نسخة لها
So you copied the birthday message Professor Takamura just sent,
فنسخت رسالة التهنئة بعيد الميلاد بالقرب التي كان البروفسور تاكامورا
which was lying nearby.
قد أرسلها لتوّه
What's more, you faxed that copy from the convenience store later.
إضافةً لذلك، أرسلت تلك النسخة بالفاكس من متجر التموينات إلى هنا لاحقاً
The copy that had the message and cake cream on it.
النسخة التي احتوت آثار الكعكة والقشدة
The owner complained that you stuck sticky paper in the machine.
اشتكى مالك المتجر من وضعك لورقة دبقة في الآلة
He also said he told you it was backwards.
كما ذكر أنّه نبهّك على كونها مقلوبة مراراً
But you can't blame him. You sent the blank side of the copy.
لكن لا عجب، فقد أرسلت الجانب الفارغ من النسخة
Because if two faxes with the same message were found at the scene,
لأنّه في حال وجود رسالتَي فاكس بنفس ،النصّ في مسرح الحريق
it would raise suspicion.
سيثير ذلك الشبهة
That's enough! I'm sick of these groundless, made-up accusations!
!يكفي! سئمتُ من هذه الاتّهامات الواهية
If you're going to make such claims, show some proof!
!إذا كنت ستواصل ادّعاءاتك، فأرني الدليل
Are you still playing innocent?
لا تزال تتظاهر بالبراءة؟
You still have the fax in question.
لا تزال تملك الفاكس المقصود معك
People certainly are strange.
البشر غريبون بحقّ
They can't easily throw away anything that could put them in danger.
لا يمكنهم إلقاء شيءٍ قد يعرّضهم للخطر بسهولة
They worry that someone else might pick it up.
يصارعون قلقهم من أخذ أحد له
You're a prime example.
أنت خير مثال
You even brought it back from the convenience store.
جلبتَه معك من متجر التموينات حتّى
Are you saying he--?!
أيمكن إذاً؟
Yes. He should still have it on him somewhere...
...أجل، لا يزال يحمله معه في مكانٍ ما
A fax with Professor Takamura's message and cake cream on it!
الفاكس برسالة البروفسور تاكامورا !وآثار القشدة
If you'll excuse us...
...اعذرنا
Don't touch me!
!لا تلمسوني
How ridiculous! I should've just thrown this thing away!
!يا للسخافة! كان عليّ التخلّص منه
T-Then it really was you?!
أ-أكان أنت حقّاً إذاً؟
Yeah. I set the fire. Using the exact method the detective explained.
أجل، أضرمتُ الحريق، بنفس الطريقة التي شرحها المتحرّي
But how did you know it was me? Anyone could've used that trick.
لكن كيف عرفت أنّه كان أنا؟ كان بإمكان أيّ أحد استعمال هذه الطريقة
Think back to when we all rushed here.
استرجع ما حصل عندما هرعنا إلى هنا
Should we call her on the phone?! She was asleep in the living room!
هل نتّصل بالهاتف ونوقظها؟ فقد كانت !نائمة في غرفة المعيشة
It's no use! It's already burned up!
!لا جدوى، لقد احترق بالفعل
I see. Only someone who knew where the fire was could've said that.
فهمت، شيء لا يقوله إلّا من عرف أين كان الحريق
But why would you do that to Asami?!
لكن لمَ قد تفعل ذلك لأسامي؟
I wanted her to love me.
أردتُها أن تحبّني
As a brave man who risked his life to rescue her from the flames.
كالرجل الشجاع الذي خاطر بحياته لإنقاذها من ألسنة اللهب
She turned me down when I asked her out last month.
رفضت طلبي بمواعدتها الشهر الفائت
That had never happened to me before, so I couldn't stand it.
لم يحصل ذلك لي قطّ قبلاً، فلم أستطع تحمّل الأمر
I'd planned for it to be a small fire, but it spread faster than I thought.
،كنت أنوي إضرام حريق صغير فحسب لكنّه انتشر أكثر مما ظننت
You fool!
!يا أحمق
Just a small fire?! It spread faster than you thought?!
!حريق صغير؟! انتشر أكثر مما ظننت؟
Do you think those serve as excuses?! You idiot!
!أتظنّ هذه أعذاراً؟! لا تعبث معي
Why couldn't you imagine Asami-san possibly burning to death?!
لمَ لم تحسب لموت أسامي-سان حرقاً؟
The car could've gotten into an accident! It could've gotten a flat tire!
!لربّما واجهت السيّارة المتوجّهة لها حادثاً !أو ثُقبت إحدى إطاراتها
There could've been a traffic jam!
!أو كان هناك ازدحام
Asami-san would've lost her life in any of those cases!
!كانت أسامي-سان لتفارقنا في أيٍّ من هذه الحالات
If you wanted her to love you,
،إذا أردت إثارة إعجابها
why didn't you consider becoming someone who could be loved?!
فلمَ لم تفكّر بأن تصبح !إنساناً يعجبها بطبيعته؟
Why didn't you consider improving yourself instead?!
!لمَ لم تفكّر بتحسين صفاتك؟
Yes. That was very stupid, President.
...بالفعل
Asami...
أسامي؟
I did something horrible.
اقترفتُ أمراً فظيعاً
I can't believe you did this for me...
...لا أصدّق أنّك فعلت هذا لأجلي
Alright. You can explain everything to the police.
هيّا، يمكنك تأجيل الكلام لحين وصولنا مركز الشرطة
Yeah.
حسناً
President.
يا رئيس
You can't open people's hearts with force.
لا يمكنك فتح أبواب قلوب الناس بالقوّة
Yeah.
صحيح
I bet you could capture any man with a single breath, though.
رغم أنّي أرجّح أنّك قادرة على خطف أيّ رجل بمجرّد نَفس لك
That's not true.
ليس صحيحاً
You just don't know about me.
فأنت لا تعرفني
Long ago, even I...
...حتّى أنا، في الماضي
...even I was...
...في الماضي
Eh?! You confessed to Shinichi-kun?!
!ماذا؟ اعترفتِ لشينتشي-كن؟
Yep. I was the one who confessed my love.
أجل، كنتُ أنا من اعترفت
He completely rejected me, though.
لكنّه رفضني تماماً
B-But the rumor said...
...لـ-لكن وفق الشائعة
Oh. I started that rumor.
كنتُ أنا من نشرها
I really wanted him to like me. He was my first love.
أردت أن أجذبه لي بأيّ شكل، فقد كان حبّي الأوّل
But he didn't seem to care about it.
لكن لم يظهر عليه أنّه مهتمّ بها البتّة
Umm, there's one thing I'd like to know...
...عذراً، هناك ما أودّ السؤال عنه
What exactly about him did you like?
ما الذي أعجبك فيه بالضبط؟
Hmm. I didn't really take notice of him at first.
حسناً، لم يخطف انتباهي حقّاً بدايةً
In his first year, he was a regular midfielder on the soccer team.
في سنته الأولى، كان لاعب وسط أساسيّ في فريق كرة القدم
I thought he was an impressive newcomer. That's about it.
ظننتُه مبتدئاً مُبهراً، لا أكثر من ذلك
But one day, I shared some lemon pie I made with the soccer club.
لكن في أحد الأيام، وزّعتُ فطيرة ليمون على أعضاء فريق كرة القدم
Everyone told me it was delicious, except for him...
...أخبرني الجميع أنّها لذيذة، باستثنائه عندما قال
Huh? This is kind of bad.
ماذا؟ هذه سيّئة نوعاً ما
Shinichi has a weird sense of taste!
!حسّ تذوّق شينتشي غريب
No. I guess it really wasn't very good at all.
كلا، أتوقّع أنّها لم تكن لذيذةً بالفعل آنذاك
Later on, everyone said they had pretended to like it.
عندما سألتُ الجميع بعد فترة، أخبروني أنّهم تظاهروا بإعجابهم بمذاقها
That hurt my feelings, so I baked a new one every day for three months
أغاظني ذلك، فصرتُ أخبز فطيرةً كلّ يوم لمدّة ثلاثة أشهر
Before I knew it, I was manager of the soccer club
ودون أن أدرك، كنت قد أصبحت مديرة نادي كرق القدم
and fascinated with him.
وأُغرمت به
Someone else made it great on her first try, though.
هناك من نجحت في محاولتها الأولى مع ذلك
Did you know? I was mean and taught you a weird way of making it!
أكنتِ تعرفين؟ تلاعبت بك وعلّمتك !طريقة غريبة لصنعها
Eh?! How come?!
ماذا؟ لمَ؟
Sheesh. Shall I tell you what he said after I confessed to him, then?
يا إلهي، هل أخبرك بما قاله بعدما اعترفت له إذاً؟
U-Umm, say--!
...ا-اسمعي
Pipe down! This is getting good! Be quiet!
!اصمت! الموضوع يصبح مثيراً الآن، فاسكت
He said this while acting embarrassed...
...قال هذا والإحراج مرسومٌ على وجهه
I'm sorry, Senpai.
آسفٌ يا سينباي
There's someone I've been fond of since I was little.
هناك من أنا مهتمٌّ بها مُذ صغري
She's strong-minded and obstinate, yet easily moved to tears.
إنّها قويّة الإرادة وعنيدة، لكن تنزل دموعها سريعاً
It's that strangeness of hers...
...غرابتها هذه هي التي
And there you have it.
وهذا ما حصل
H-Hold on, Ran! Could that be--?!
ا-انتظري يا ران! أيمكن أنّ تلك...؟
Do you remember a girl like that?
أتذكرين فتاةً كهذه؟
Huh?
ماذا؟
Oh well.
...لا يهمّ
Don't play dumb, Okita!
!لا تتظاهر بالحماقة يا أوكيتا
We saw Nagakura Isami-san collapse on the veranda from your room!
رأينا إيسامي-سان تنهار !على الفرشة في غرفتك
It definitely looks like Okita-san killed her.
يبدو أنّ الفاعل هو أكيتا-سان حقّاً
Wait a minute! Could this incident be--?!
...انتظر، أيمكن أنّ هذه القضيّة
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Historical Drama Actor Murder Case (Part 1)."
جريمة قتل مُمثل الدراما التاريخيّة (الجزء الأوّل)
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Phone.
هاتف